A Guide to the Duke Family Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE
  - SUBSERIES F: MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE
    - John S. Mosby to R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1915 Sep 27 (Box Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous Letters to R. T. W. Duke, Sr., 1883-1895, & n.d. (Box Box 23)
    - Letters from R. T. W. Duke, Sr., 1880-1894 (Box Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence of the Duke and Related Families, 1866-1976 & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 23)
    - Susan Harker Risdon to the Duke Family, 1887-1899, & n.d. (Box Box 23)
    - Kathleen Timmons to the Duke Family, 1918-1940, & n.d. (Box Box 23)
    - Letters from the Lee Family, 1895-1954, & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous Harker Family Correspondence, 1856-1916, & n.d. (Box Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous Letters to "Mary", 1910-1927, & n.d. (Box Box 24)
    - Non-Duke Family Correspondence, 1875-1982, & n.d. (Box Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous Letter Fragments, 1888-1905, & n.d. (Box Box 24)
  - SUBSERIES G: TOPICAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - American Legion and World War I Papers, 1920 & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 24)
    - Chiefly Business Correspondence of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1922-1926; (3 folders) (Box Box 24)
    - Correspondence of Mary Duke re Publication of the Poetry of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1926-1929 (Box Box 24)
    - Correspondence re Rental of the Park Street House, 1927-1941 (Box Box 24)
    - Correspondence re the will of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1925-1927 (Box Box 24)
    - St. Paul's Memorial Building Fund, 1920-1935 (Box Box 24)
- SERIES II: MANUSCRIPTS & MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
  - Business Papers of the Duke & Related Families, 1809, 1862-1983, & n.d.; (8 folders) (Box Box 25)
  - Genealogical Material re the Duke and Related Families, 1823-1963, & n.d. (Box Box 26)
  - Invitations, 1872-1957, & n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 26)
  - Legal Papers of the Duke & Related Families, 1764, 1794, 1873-1983, & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 27)
  - "Albemarle County and the City of Charlottesville in War Time A Community History" by R. T. W. Duke, Jr. (Box Box 27)
  - "Libraries and Their Contents," by R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1919 Nov 27 (Box Box 27)
  - Manuscripts of Judge R. T. W. Duke, Jr. -- Poetry, 1874-1914, & n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 27)
  - Manuscripts of Judge R. T. W. Duke, Jr. -- Prose, 1914 & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 28)
  - "Pearls and Pebbles," quotations collected by R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1873-1875 (Box Box 28)
  - Typescript of the diaries of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1893, 1914-1916, & 1926 (Box Box 28)
  - Typescript of "Recollections," Volumes I-III, by R. T. W. Duke, Jr., with excerpts from his diaries, ca. 1899 (Box Box 29)
  - Typescript of "Recollections," part of Volume I, by R. T. W. Duke, Jr., ca. 1899 (Box Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous Duke Family Manuscripts, 1918 & n.d. (Box Box 29)
  - Manuscripts of Mary H. Harker, 1850-1852, & n.d. (Box Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts, 1860-1972, & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous Papers of the Duke Family, 1845-1955, & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 29)
  - Printed Material, 1847-1966, & n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 30)
  - Duke Family School Records, 1870-1912 (Box Box 30)
  - Duke Family School Papers, 1877-1927 (Box Box 30)
- SERIES III: PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Judge R. T. W. Duke, Jr., n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - R. T. W. Duke, Sr., 1895 & n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Men in the Duke and Related Families, 1871 & n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Women in the Duke and Related Families, 1878-1903, & n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Rosalie Slaughter Morton, 1872 & n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous Men, 1887-1931, & n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous Women, 1888-1980, & n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - European Scenes, 1918-1921 (Box Box 31)
  - Places, 1915, 1923, & n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Photographs of a Trip, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - University of Virginia, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Zeta Psi Brothers and University of Virginia Friends, 1872-1881 (Box Box 32)
  - Unidentified Photographs - Animals, 1940 & n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Unidentified Photographs - Children, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Unidentified Photographs - Groups & Families, 1887, 1963, & n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Unidentified Photographs - Men, 1905-1937, & n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Unidentified Photographs - Places, n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Unidentified Photographs - Women, 1886-1953, & n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 33)
  - Unidentified Negatives, n.d. (Box Box 33)
- SERIES IV: BOUND VOLUMES & NOTEBOOKS
  - Account Book, 1907 (Box Box 34)
  - Account Books of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1910 Aug & Sep; (2 vols.) (Box Box 34)
  - Autograph Album of Mary Harker, 1849 (Box Box 34)
  - Autograph Album of Susan Harker, ca. 1855 (Box Box 34)
  - Cashbook of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., ca. 1893 (Box Box 34)
  - Communicant's Book Belonging to John S. Duke, 1907 (Box Box 34)
  - Daily Account Books of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1906, 1912-1913, 1917-1918 & 1920; (6 vols.) (Box Box 34)
  - Diaries of Edith Duke, 1887, 1896, 1911-1912 & 1915; (5 vols.) (Box Box 34)
  - Diaries of Helen Duke, 1956-1957; (2 vols.) (Box Box 34)
  - Diaries of John S. Duke, 1905-1907; (3 vols.) (Box Box 34)
  - Diaries of Mary Duke, 1908, 1917, & 1925; (3 vols.) (Box Box 34)
  - Diaries of R. T. Walker Duke, III, 1904-1905; (2 vols.) (Box Box 34)
  - Diary of William Eskridge Duke, 1954 (Box Box 34)
  - Diary, 1963 (Box Box 34)
  - Diary, 1970 (Box Box 35)
  - Diary recording food purchases, kept by [Edith Duke], 1887 (Box Box 35)
  - Financial Notebook of Eskridge, Helen & Mary Duke re land sales, 1955-1959 (Box Box 35)
  - Garden Book, 1932-1936 (Box Box 35)
  - Journal of R. T. W. Duke, Jr. of thoughts re his wife, Edith, 1914 (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook - Calendar, [1968?] (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook - Financial, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook of Helen Duke (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook of John S. Duke, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook of Mary Duke, 1897-1898 (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1910 Mar (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook (School) of R. T. Walker Duke, III, 1905 (Box Box 35)
  - Notebook of Mary H. Harker, 1851 (Box Box 35)
  - Notebooks, 1883, 1895, 1925, 1975, n.d.; (7 vols.) (Box Box 35)
  - Passport of Helen Duke, 1929 (Box Box 35)
  - Recipes, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Record Book of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., ca. 1890-1894 (Box Box 35)
  - Sketchbook of Mary Duke, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Travel Log of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., 1910 Oct (Box Box 35)
  - Bound Volume of typescripts of the Poetry of R. T. W. Duke, Jr., later published as In My Library and Other Poems (Box Box 36)
  - Scrapbooks, n.d.; (2 volumes) (Box Box 36)
- SERIES V: POSTCARDS
  - A) United States: (Box Box 37)
    Florida -New Smyrna
    Maine -Boothbay Harbor and Portland
    Massachusetts -Plymouth
    New Jersey -Atlantic City
    New York -Long Island; Manhattan; Niagara Falls; Tonawanda; New York City Booklets
    North Carolina -Black Mountain and Roanoke Rapids
    South Carolina -Charleston
    Texas -San Antonio
    Vermont -Montpelier
    Virginia -Afton; Alexandria; Annapolis; Appomattox; Arlington; Charlottesville; General; Giles County; Hampton; Hopewell; Monticello; Natural Bridge; Newport News; Richmond; Skyline Drive; Staunton; University of Virginia; Virginia Beach; Williamsburg; Winchester
    Washington, D.C.
  - B) Foreign: (Box Box 37)
    Algeria
    Canada
    Carthage (Ancient)
    China
    Egypt
    France
    Germany
    Gibraltar
    Great Britain
    Greece
    Israel
    Italy
    Monaco
    Portugal (Madeira)
    Spain
    Tunisia
    Turkey
    Unidentified
  - C) Topical (Box Box 37)
- SERIES VI: PAPERS FROM THE DUKE & DUKE LAW FIRM
  - Miscellaneous Legal Cases of the Duke & Duke Law Firm, 1883-1938 (Box Box 38)
  - Valdosia Barrett letters, 1921-1924, & n.d. (Box Box 38)
  - Maria Carter vs Roy Brown, 1928 (Box Box 38)
  - J.E. Costan vs Downing L. Smith, 1926 (Box Box 38)
  - Dr. Funsten vs W. Ed Pickering, 1935 (Box Box 38)
  - Insurance Company of Charlottesville vs V.W.F. Carter, Jr., 1925-1931 (Box Box 38)
  - Kentucky Coal Company, Pike County Coal Company, & Ohio and Big Sandy Coal Company, 1894-1896 (Box Box 38)
  - Jefferson M. Levy Legal Papers, 1892-1917; (2 folders) (Box Box 38)
  - Piedmont Gas & Oil Corporation vs R.S. Duncan, 1934-1935 (Box Box 38)
  - Snyder vs the University of Virginia, ca. 1900 (Box Box 38)
- SERIES VII: OVERSIZE ITEMS
  - A) Miscellaneous
    - Virginia Military Institute Diploma of Col. R.T.W. Duke, Sr., 1845
    - Passport of R.T.W. Duke, Jr., signed by Fred T. Frelinghuysen, 1882
    - Plat of portion of Carlton land sold by the Charlottesville Land Company to Jefferson M. Levy, 1892
    - Masonic document appointing R.T.W. Duke, Jr. the Virginia representative of the Grand Royal Arch Chapter of West Virginia, 1896
    - Plat of the Brown Brothers land, [1907]
    - Certificate of Promotion from the Charlottesville High School issued to Eskridge Duke, 1907-1908
    - Certificate of Distinction from the Charlottesville High School in Ancient History, Rhetoric and Latin, issued to Eskridge Duke, 1908
    - Plans for Remodeling Judge R.T.W. Duke, Jr.'s residence by Waddy B. Wood, n.d.
  - B) Photographs
    - Woman and two boys in colonial costume posed on the Lawn in front of the Rotunda, [post 1895]
    - Surgeon's Club, Rochester, Minnesota, including Rosalie Slaughter Morton, 1911
    - Virginia State Bar Association Annual Meeting at White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia (Judge Duke is slightly right of center), 1915
    - Meeting of the Medical Women's National Association, ca. 1926
    - Group posed on a lawn in front of a [hotel?] (including Judge Duke in the upper center of the group), n.d.
    - Painting of a church in Williamsburg, Virginia by W. Thompson in the Metropolitan Museum of Art, n.d.
    - Group photograph of R.T.W. Duke, Jr. with four unidentified men., n.d.
- MINI-TRAY ITEMS
  - Small round hand-painted scene of a mountain, woods, & lake on cardboard, n.d., 1)
  - British War Relief Society Bookmark of red, white, & blue, w/a blue tassel, 2)
  - Metal Namecard Master belonging to Sue Harker, 3)
  - Metal Plate used to produce invitations to a function held by Mary H. Harker, 4)